# **Martha Chamberlain**

#### FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

## CONTACT



marthachamberlain444 @gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ mchamberlain444



github.com/MarthaC444



portfolio.marthachamberlain .com

## **EDUCATION**

Colorado Registered Web Dev Apprenticeship Techtonic Group Inc. Boulder, CO | 2019 - 2020

Liberal Arts Courses Delta College Saginaw, MI | 1996 - 1998

# **SKILLS**

- Semantic HTML5, CSS
- Javascript
- React
- git/GitHub
- Bootstrap, MUI, NativeBase
- Responsive layouts
- SEO/accessibility

## **INTERESTS**

Executing an enjoyable user experience, gardening, hiking, organizing anything

## **PROFILE**

Front End web developer experienced with Agile CI/CD cross functional collaborative environments, and self motivated, independent work.

Comfortable with continuous learning - an excellent fit for a junior front-end or entry level full-stack development role.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

SELF EMPLOYED | HAMPTON, TN | April 2020 - present

- Built a demo WordPress CMS multi-site marthachamberlain.com
- Building a dashboard based web app Next, Supabase/PostgreSQL,
   Typescript, React, MUI
- Building my personal portfolio site. Challenged myself to build "from scratch" with a CRA base and a front end framework - React SPA, Javascript, React Bootstrap, Cypress testing
- Built a marketing site for a hobby farm. Communicates client's mission and philosophy, and beautifully showcases the client's organic free range heritage breed fowl - HTML, CSS, Javascript, Web Components, Bootstrap 5

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER I

TECHTONIC | BOULDER, CO | March 2020 - April 2020 (covid)

 Upgraded client's static demo mobile app to consume and display live data, allowing managers to visualize 'on the ground' water park conditions in real time - React Native, Redux, Javascript, Android Studio, Xcode, git, GitHub, RESTful API, JIRA/Confluence

#### WEB DEVELOPER APPRENTICE

TECHTONIC | BOULDER, CO | June 2019 - March 2020

- Improved the Techtonic marketing website collaborating with marketing dept and QA to add new features, update web content, and fix bugs -HTML, Sass, Bulma, jQuery, Butter CMS, git, GitHub, JIRA/Confluence
- Met classroom project deadlines and quality requirements setting a solid foundation in coding fundamentals, problem-solving, team collaboration and independent research - HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, React/Redux, MongoDB, RESTful API, Bootstrap, git, GitHub, JIRA/Confluence, Cypress testing